So, if you have custom word lists that
you manage, go take these right now and
add them to your custom word list
because they're known good files that
have leaked passwords in the past.
>> Best part of hacking when you can just,
you know, critical think
[Music]
One of the cool things about going to
these live hacking events is the ability
to look at what you found and what other
people have found and understand where
the holes are in your methodology,
right? By comparing notes. Um, and
thanks to Adobe sponsoring this episode
today, we have an opportunity very
similar to that for you guys. Okay, so
here's how this is going to work. Adobe
has agreed to give you guys a 10%
onetime bonus on your first valid report
to any of the following products. Listen
closely. Adobe Behance, Adobe Portfolio,
Adobe Fonts, Acrobat Web. Okay, those
four. And to get that, you have to use
the code CTBP0907.
Okay, the the description will have that
information. Also, this is valid through
September 7th, right? So, keep that in
mind. Then, what we're going to do on
top of that is we're going to do a
hackalong in the CTB Discord for
everybody, okay? And we're going to
start looking at these targets. And so
what'll happen then is you guys will
take a look at it. You'll see what you
can find. Then we'll do the hackalong
and everybody will be hacking on them,
finding vulnerabilities. I'll be hacking
on them, finding vulnerabilities. And
then we can compare notes and see where
we missed the sketchy pieces of uh
information or the leads or the
vulnerabilities themselves. Okay, so
really good opportunity. This is the
kind of stuff that we have at live
hacking events and Adobe is bringing
this to you guys. So definitely check
out those targets. They're in the
description along with the code. Also,
the Adobe team wants me to let you know
that they're going to be at Besides Las
Vegas sponsoring August 4th, August 5th.
Come check it out. Go to their booth,
have a chat with them. They'll also be
at Defcon in the Bug Downey Village. Um,
so if you see anybody with like Adobe
swag or whatever, don't hesitate to come
up and say hi. All right, that's it.
Thank you, Adobe. Back to the show.
>> Yo, what's up, dude? I got
>> I got to tune in on your hackalong this
morning and it seemed like it was going
uh pretty well and then you told me
right after I hopped off you all found a
bunch of bugs. So if people are not uh
in critical thinking doing hackalongs,
they should hop in there.
>> Dude, it was a lot of fun. And every
every time we do those things, it's not
me fighting the bug typically. It's the
people in the in the chat. like I'm over
just kind of like, you know, screwing
around with something and and typically
like I'll find a bug or I'll find um you
know, at least some good gadgets or some
fun functionality. Um but almost every
single time we we we do the hackalong,
somebody finds a bug, a portable bug.
>> Um but yeah, this time I did find some
some cool stuff and uh Beex, shout out
to Beex, found a couple XSS and so you
know, we have some results from this
one.
>> Yeah, that's amazing. I um I thought
that that was interesting the way that
you you like went down that initial
rabbit hole in that random domain. So
>> yeah. Yeah. It's it's it's fun, dude.
It's fun. I mean like I I I wish I could
say it perfectly represents hacking
because it it doesn't you know when when
you're trying to do a stream and you're
trying to you know um
>> talk manage chat.
>> Yeah. Exactly. You're trying to manage
chat. You're trying to you know like for
me it's very hard to hack and talk at
the same time. I'm getting better at it.
you definitely gotten better at it since
we started critical thinking, but um
it's very hard. Uh and I definitely feel
my processing power go down. Um
>> yeah, but let me let me ask you an
interesting question. Let's say that you
said, "Hey, we're going to take those
same people and let them all hack for an
hour, you plus them." Do you think you
would find more bugs doing the hackalong
collectively? Or would the you plus
those people all hacking for an hour and
a half find more bugs independently?
>> I I would have a very strong opinion
here.
I have a very strong opinion. Yeah,
>> I don't know, man. You know how I do. I
I I do prefer I do love the power of
just focus and sitting down and like
locking in and and stuff like that. But
definitely, you know, when with the
collective brain of everybody, you know,
everybody's going to see something a
little bit different and somebody's
going to have that eye to pull out, you
know, a crazy crazy endpoint or uh quirk
or API key or something like that. So
>> I I think that you I think that
collectively there's way more bugs found
during hackalong
>> even with the level of talent that was
there and I think that it's because um
there's like this shared perception
sense where like you're handing off
gadgets to people who are the best at
those gadgets naturally because like
when someone's paying attention to the
stream and they see something that
they're like kind of a pseudo expert at
they're going to like key in on that
>> and then when people find things that
you're particularly good at they surface
it to you and then you go look at it. So
anyways I think it's really cool. I
think more people should do more
hackalongs.
>> Well, I was going to say, you know,
there I'll give a shout out to Demo and
and uh You mean Turbo?
>> Yeah, Turbo. Exactly. Demo. Turbo. My
boy needs to get his aliases in place,
but um Demo is there for every hackalong
>> and and he um
>> he always finds some crazy stuff, you
know, that I that I missed. And uh yeah,
and he's going to be doing a a talk at
Bugani Village under the alias Turbo
with seven for the T
>> on Saturday at noon. Yeah, on Saturday
at noon. Um, so definitely check that
out. It's going to be awesome. Um, he is
a very high skill hacker. Um, but yeah,
man. I I've I've always been impressed
by the hackalongs. It's a fun time. But
we have a [__] ton of content to get to
today. So, let's jump into that. Um,
>> let's do it.
>> Since we've got a lot of guest episodes,
this one's going to be more of like a
news catchup episode. Um, yeah,
>> because we had the Valentino episode,
we've got Dorado coming soon, we've got
some others coming up.
Are you just leaking our whole calendar
right now? Dude,
>> Valentino came out today. I leaked one
person and you already mentioned that
last time. No,
>> I didn't mention it last time. Did I
mention it last time?
>> I don't know. But I I told people I told
personal people that I thought it was
coming out this week and I was wrong. So
hopefully it comes out next week.
>> Yeah. Well, I I'm going to shuffle them
around a little bit. So anyway, all
right. Fine. We We do have an Expo
related episode in the queue. It is
already recorded. It is going to come
out eventually, but we're we're working
on some of the details. So, um All
right. Let's let let's get to some of
the content here. Um there was a a write
up that surfaced uh not too long ago. Um
that was back from 2019 and uh I want to
say it was Victor I forget the last name
but uh that that tweeted about it and
kind of brought it up from the dead. Uh
and I I just wanted to highlight it on
the pod because I really like this type
of vulnerability. This is a um instance
metadata service protection bypass in
Google Cloud. And for any of you guys
that know, you know, about uh metadata
URLs, this is a huge part of SSRF
exploitation in a cloud environment
where um you know, you often will hit
these metadata URLs and get back
instance uh metadata about the the given
instance you're on in in a cloud
environment. Um and there have been some
protections that have been put in place
by by Google and by AWS now um to
prevent us from hitting those metadata
URLs as easily. Um, and this
vulnerability from 2019 was when that
those protections first came out, the
metadata flavor um header being
required, which you often can't specify
in an SSRF environment.
Um, and it was three bypasses to that
behavior. Uh, the the first one um was
simply by adding an extra slash to the
URL
under compute metadata. So, compute
metadata slashv1 instanceame.
Um, which is just so dumb.
>> Insane. Insane.
>> Unbelievably dumb. Uh, and then how does
that how does that affect whether it's
checking for the header or not? That
doesn't make any sense.
>> Like some sort of reverse proxy
middleware must be, you know, which is
very telling about the implementation of
this at GCP.
>> Um, then he does it again with HTTP1.
Then he does it again with just a random
semicolon in the URL.
Um, and so each of those were accepted
by by um by Google VRP and paid a
bounty. And I just wanted to highlight
them because, you know, you definitely
want to spend time fuzzing these things
in all sorts of ways. Adding slashes,
adding semicolons, trying HTTP0,
especially when it's high impact pieces
of of architecture like the metadata
URL. Mhm.
>> Um, these are the things we must know
about. And and if this person had kept
this in their pocket for a long time, so
many vulnerabilities would
>> That's what I was thinking. This feels
almost like a bad move.
>> This, you know, like like I totally get
reporting it. Um, and I and I wouldn't
tell them to do anything but report it,
but like if a malicious actor got a hold
of this, that would be a very different
story. So
>> farable bug. Um,
>> yeah. Yeah. Very exploitable. So
definitely high impact stuff found here.
And I think that sort of attack scope is
really interesting for cloud
environments.
>> Yeah, it makes me wonder how many things
like this are out there. Sure, there are
plenty.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> Sweet. Um, we can jump to one of my
smaller ones.
>> Um, our friends Ian Carol and Sam Curry
uh released a blog post like yesterday
or the day before across a few different
social media platforms. I'll share my
screen as I click through this real
quick.
>> It's called Would You Like an ID Door
With That? Makes me think of the song.
Do you know the Do you know the old
McDonald's song? The rap.
>> The what?
>> The rap. The McDonald's rap like a
double cheeseburger and hold the
lettuce. Don't be fronting some no makes
me think of that.
>> Dude, I haven't heard that in forever.
That's such a throwback. Wow.
>> All right, here we go. Um, it's probably
kind of wide. I guess more.
>> Um, yeah. So, they titled their blog
post, would you like an IDOR with that
leaking 64 million McDonald's job
applications?
>> Yeah. So basically the prospective
employees who want to like get hired by
McDonald's can chat with this chatbot
called Olivia and it's made by this
company called Paradox AI. And so that's
actually probably where the
vulnerability really was. But um
essentially it's like not that
interesting of a bug. It's just an idor
but their their process of finding it
was interesting and it involved having
default credentials of one to six as
both the username and the password.
But um but yeah, so like they got in
from the admin side and then they also
applied for it from the user side and
then eventually from the user side they
saw this uh put request that involved uh
a lead ID and their lead ID was 64
million. So they just they decremented
it
>> and uh found other users actual like
phone numbers and actual like the
conversations with the AI agent. So I
have a theory here. I wonder if this is
not just McHire's I think it's like the
entire Paradox AI database. Um because
64 million is a lot even for McDonald's.
Like how many employees do McDonald's
even have
>> in the US like like applying for a job
at McDonald's? I don't think that's
right.
>> Right. Like uh they have 2 million
people worldwide. And so I mean I guess
they could have some turnover and it
could add up that amount. I mean there's
even if it is the third party McDonald's
is probably their biggest um vendor or
whatever that like their biggest
customer. But anyways, I thought that
was really interesting. And if you think
about it, I was like, man, this is an AI
system that has had 64 million unique
users or 64 million, you know, cases or
whatever outside of the major providers
and maybe like cursor and stuff. I
wonder if this is like one of the most
used AI apps. They said they tried
prompt injection and it was like really
really railroaded like it didn't it
couldn't do anything interesting. So, it
might not even be like an LLM backed
app. could just be, you know, those old
agent systems that like AWS and GCP and
everything had even before LLMs where it
was like a support, you know, a
railroaded support system. But,
>> right,
>> anyways, I thought it was interesting.
>> Yeah, that is definitely an interesting
one. I I uh I hate hate to see the
default credentials of 1 2 3 4 56 uh
>> for a system that sensitive. I mean,
come on.
>> Yeah, that's uh pretty egregious, not
going to lie. Um but very cool
nonetheless. I love the little stunt
hacks that uh that Sam and Ian do for
fun that they just pone some company
completely. Um and sometimes it's as
simple as like you know an Idor here or
sometimes it's like all the crazy stuff
they throw together.
>> Yeah. Like all the car hacks. I mean
that stuff is really really valuable.
Like this one I think is more for fun
but when you think about the stuff
they've done they've done for the
airline industry and the car industry. I
think it makes like a really material
difference to like all of our lives when
they're responsibly disclosing that
stuff. So
>> 100% man definitely definitely securing
stuff up a lot. Um okay so next on the
list is Christmas in July with
Searchlight Cyber. Um the Search Light
Cyber team is releasing a bunch of
research in July which is super cool.
Yeah.
>> Um they're two in. So we'll cover those
now uh as we're recording and then
hopefully we'll cover the other ones
before Defcon. Um, but this first one
was how we got precision XSS on every AM
cloud site thrice, which is which is
lit. Um, and there were a couple things
I wanted to highlight from this one. Um,
the first one is is that I think that
this is a really cool technique that
they're using here that um, we've kind
of discussed a bit in the research lab
for critical thinking. Um, and it where
and we call these sort of crossc
customer vulnerabilities, right?
where um there's you know you're able to
host something uh like in this specific
scenario they're they're referencing an
npm package right that and they're
loading JS from it but you're able to
host something on a different um service
and then the thing you're attacking has
like a reverse proxy uh to that service
um for the purpose of grabbing data
related to the the user itself um but
actually you can reference you know some
other user of that service and and and
pull down some data Um so so what what's
happening here is uh they have this path
on AM cloud that's supposed to serve JS
files from from the JSCDN
>> and they found that you're able to
upload HTML files to that CDN and then
reference those HTML files underneath
the path of every single AM cloud site.
Um
>> and and I'll just read this little this
little snippet here to make sure I'm I'm
extra clear about it. While doing bug
bounty on a site running a am a am a am
a am a am a am a am a am a am a am a am
we noticed that the site was loading
some javascript from the route slash.rum
adobe helixrumdistrum
standstandalone.js. Further digging
indicated that the slash.rum path was
handled by Adobe's cloudspecific CDN
configuration and appear to be proxying
directly to the npm package host. Our
interest was peaked as npm packages can
contain HTML files. they may allow for
an XSS and I just think that is such a
beautiful example of very ingenuative
attack vector ideation.
>> Yeah. In fact, I think like the frame
here that everyone should be taking away
from this is like if you have some sort
of SAS like that allows you to, you
know, spin up your own tenant or your
own host. So there's a million of those,
right? Like
>> Workday, Service Now, Salesforce, but
then the list is like near infinite.
There are thousands. And then if they in
any point are using stuff hosted on like
a third party or a domain or a CDN
domain and not only your subdomain. So
you can literally go hunt for this by
just looking for apps that have a lot of
functionality where you can upload
things or modify a lot of content and
then just see if they get hosted on a
shared domain that the other customers
use as well. Now all of a sudden you
have like a really strong gadget that
would end up doing something like this.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. And so I I think just
from the start, you know, the kind of
vulnerabilities that the um you know,
search light cyber team here looking for
just very good and this is the how how
you do um you know really impactful
security research here. Um and and then
they take that and you know they
validate their assumption. They were
able to pop um uh you know the XSS on
unpackage that was happily serving text
HTML content type. Um, and then they go
and look at the logic of how exactly
this um, you know, route is being
essentially remapped to the CDN. Um, and
as they're going through here, they find
three different bypasses. One is a
missing slash at the end of a path that
uses path.st starts with pretty classic
uh, vulnerability. And the but the other
ones are um, a lot more interesting, I
thought. um after after it was patched,
they actually ended up using um a
technique that I think is really widely
applicable, which is the fact that uh
fetch will take any
um new line or tab character that's in a
URL and just remove it. So if you do dot
tab dot slash, that will become a path
traversal. Um, so, so let's say there's
some logic that's say checking for dot
dot slash before you, you know, it
passes to fetch. You can pass in dot,
you know, actual tab character dot
slash.
>> Yep.
>> And then it will pass the reax, but then
when it gets to fetch, the SL the tab
will be deleted and it will do the the
normalization.
>> That sounds like a relatively big deal.
>> Yeah.
>> Have you have you ever used that before?
>> I I I think I have used it without
realizing what was happening. Um, which
kind of funny. like found organically
just by fuzzing looking for characters,
what works, what doesn't. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And they, you know, they traced it
all the way down to um let's see this
add a URL parser library. Um and then
mentioned that uh you know fetch was
utilizing this. So um with that they
were able to bypass again and then um
they were also able to utilize some um
normalization gadgets um within that
reverse or that reverse proxy
environment where you know you'll hit
hit a specific path that 302s but when
it 302s it actually normalizes part of
your URL encoded um content. So
>> yeah,
>> really really cool stuff that they're
that they're doing there. And I think a
lot of those techniques are are really
um applicable
>> uh to to other sort of exploitation
scenarios.
>> Yeah, you've been all about this. I feel
like on the hackalong today, you were
also talking a lot about this like just
like when it comes to string parsing,
all the different unique characters you
can fuzz for or test for or you know
break out of like I I I feel like that's
almost like the the core part of hacking
that you kind of think about these days.
>> Yeah, I I think about it a lot. It's
it's very interesting. And I did have
one more thing I wanted to mention on
this before we we move to the next one.
Um, see if I can find it right here. I
got search for it. But the way that they
got this to work was super awesome. Um,
oh, here it is right here. So, there
were two um, CDNs, JavaScript CDNs that
were serving these JS files.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, but only one of them work. Only
unpackage served to the HTML content
type. JS deliver did not. And so uh they
found that it was actually caching the
response but they didn't want the
incorrect uh you know response to get
cached. Yeah. And so they went to the
like they kept researching until they
found a way a difference between JS
Deliver and unpackage that would force
it to
>> oh my goodness like like a cache
difference between the two servers.
>> Yes. And they on JS Deliver if you put
all caps in the name it's it's case
sensitive. So it would 404 but on
unpackage it's not case sensitive.
caps. Yeah. And it would get the
response. So that's awesome.
>> Uh it was freaking beautiful, man. Bravo
to the search light cyber team. Again,
>> who is doing the majority of the hacking
there? Obviously Shubs does, but who
else do you know?
>> Yeah. Geez. I mean this the guy that
wrote this one is Adam Kuz. Um so I'm
not sure I'm not sure who exactly is
doing that. I know Shubs does have his
hands on all this. And I imagine since
the beginning of this was uh from Bug
Bounty um then it it was probably
related to that.
>> Yeah. I I heard uh chevs mention Adam a
lot so I'm sure he's one of the main
guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Sweet. Um one this little really small
thing here was the just a tweet from
James Cuddle. Um and he was talking
about how Google Docs support exporting
as Markdown. They've had paste as
Markdown for a while but now that you
can you can export as Markdown. you can
use like really nice um like auto
formatterers that will just change like
markdown to HTML or whatever. So, um
yeah, really nice. I personally really
love markdown. I love just plain text
files. So, if you you know that's a
common thing that a lot of bug bunny
hunters are using for their notes or
whatever.
>> Oh, dude. I'm I'm glad you mentioned
that because that's like kind of like a
tool, right? Um not as much as like a
hacking technique. And I actually had
something that I wanted to bring up
related to that. Um, I use that feature
all the time, by the way. The copy is
marked down. Like, they didn't I didn't
even see like a change log or anything.
I just right clicked one day and I was
like, "No way. Copy is marked down."
>> Um, so that's awesome. But the one that
I was going to tell you about was
Raycast for Windows, man.
>> Raycast. Um,
>> came out on Windows.
>> Yes, it came out on Windows.
>> Are you using it? I've got it already.
I've got it. Yeah. And guess what?
>> Did you convert like your whole stack to
it yet or what?
>> I did. I converted my stack to it. I've
got all of my like URL encoding stuff,
all of my like quick clipboard operation
imported into Raycast
>> uh with AI, not very long, couple hours.
Okay. Um but it's it's pretty great. Uh
there definitely are going to be some
improvements that are needed, but the
the Raycast team is moving pretty fast.
And they gave me um they gave me 15 uh
Windows invites to give out.
>> Oh, that's awesome.
>> To the beta. So, uh I don't know how
should we do this. Should we say like um
maybe I'll put out a tweet um on or no
no I'll put it in the Discord. I'll put
something in the Discord that says hey
you know respond to this message and uh
we'll get you you know one of the
Windows invites if you want.
>> Um so Richard remind me to do that. I I
don't want to write it down right now
but uh we'll definitely put that out
there if you guys want access to Raycast
for Windows.
>> Correct. I had one more kind of small
toolsy thing before we go to another
real one. Um, basically I saw someone
tweet that, you know, it's better
prompting etiquette to um say like name
of assistant does X instead of uh you
know you do X
>> because uh you know model providers like
Claude do this um like they they in
their instructions say like Claude does
this, Claude does that, Claude does
this. And I thought that was really
interesting. Wow. Sorry, I'm getting a
phone call. This is really loud in my
ears. Um and um so someone else was
like, "Oh, that's so obvious." And so
then that person had like a big
following. So then they quote tweeted
like with like a survey that was like,
"Do you in your prompt injection or
jailbreaks, whatever or just in your
system prompts put like you know the app
name does X or you do X and like it was
95% that like you do." And I noticed in
my and I used I noticed in my prompting
I always do that like you should respond
this way, you should do that. And um the
fact that Anthropic who's done like you
know probably more studies on this than
anyone is using it the other way. I
think it's actually great to do it the
other way. And so anyways as you're
hacking as you're using prompt injection
payloads as you're using jailbreaks
whatever if you know the system which
you often do like let's say you're
hacking on Google you would say Gemini
does this or Gemini responds this way or
what have you. Um, or at the very least
just try both because if in their system
prompt it's like all, you know, first
person Claude does this,
>> then you switch it to second person and
say you do this, it's going to be very
obvious to the model to know that that's
not Huh.
>> Yeah. Third first person is second
person's you, right?
>> Second person is you, third person is
Claude, right?
>> Right. Yeah. So it' be third person.
Yeah. So if the system prompt is in
third person and then you switch to
second, it's going to probably be
jarring to the model and it'll be it'll
know. Whereas if you try third person,
then all of a sudden Yeah. Actually, I
wonder if any of them do use first
person. Like if they say something like,
"I really like to respond with all caps
and I really know a lot about this in
and it's like internal system prompt."
>> It kind of makes sense though if you
think about how it's processing at
inference because that's how our
thoughts are sometimes.
>> Huh.
>> Anyways,
>> random little prompting technique there.
>> That is nice. I like that. Yeah, it
makes sense that you should match what
the system prompt is, especially if you
want to blend in with the system prompt.
>> Yeah. And if you don't know, just try
both. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Good [__] All right. Next
up, um, back to search light cyber
Christmas in July. Their, um, their
writeup, uh, was entitled, abusing
Windows.net works in Unicornalization to
exploit .NET Nuke. Um, and so
essentially the the concept here is
they've been kind of exploiting some
vulnerabilities lately, it seems, with
file.exist, which will make um, which
when you can provide an absolute path to
it, will connect to a window share and
leak the NLM hash. Right.
>> Classic technique. Y
>> um and and so they're doing a little
research uh on how exactly all that
works. They found an unauthenticated
endpoint on on net that will um handle a
file upload. And there's a bunch of
restrictions in place on this. It takes
any special character um and it removes
it with a rejax and puts it as an
underscore. It cleans up the file name.
It validates the characters.
>> Excuse me. But then right here at the
very end after all of that sanitization
it does utility.convert unicode
characters uh and then passes in the
file name which is just lovely. Um and
essentially what's happening here is
after all of the sanitization they do
unic code normalization uh which will
can allow you to just take you know unic
code characters like
>> oh rip it had it should have been at the
beginning right? Oh man,
>> exactly. It take full width dot and
convert it into a dot, you know, do
whatever, right? Um, so the team was
able to utilize this to to exploit um
and get an NLM off hash leak. Um, which
which I thought was pretty awesome. So,
always want to shout that out. Order of
sanitization is really important. Um,
and as I was sort of reading the code
for this, I I'll put it up on the screen
here. You can see that um the convert
unicode uh characters function here um
does a bunch of regular expression to
convert unicode characters and then
right here it just sort of does a
general conversion. Um but one of the
things that was really interesting to me
was this piece down here at the end
which replaces um question marks with
string empty uh tabs with string empty
uh slash r uh with string empty back
slashn as string empty right and anytime
I see something getting moved to you
know getting replaced to string empty I
think oh
>> I need to be using that as a as a as a
way to bypass stuff for example like
what we talked about earlier with you
know dot
>> tab dot right
>> that's exactly where my mind went it's
like oh that's like very similar code to
that thing we were just talking about
>> exactly exactly and if you if you look
earlier up you know they cover this
because you you can only have one dot in
this whole um string anyway so it's
covered in this scenario but I wanted to
to shout it out again is that you know
in these replacement scenarios where
there's there's taking some sensitive um
or malicious string potentially and
replacing it with empty, you definitely
have to be able to utilize that as an
attacker sometimes to get path reversal
or sneak in some character sequences
that have meaning to the application.
>> Yep. Yeah, makes sense.
>> Yeah. Um, really good article. Um, let
me see if I had anything else on all of
that. Um, yeah, I mean it was it was a
pretty clean one. I mean, the the NLM
hash leak strategy, you know, if you're
not familiar with that, you must know
what that does. So, definitely research
that if you're not. um order of
operations in in sanitization and then
look for replaces to empty strings that
you can use to sneak in malicious
character sequences.
>> All right,
>> I really need to I really need to look
for more unic code normalization stuff.
It's always like
>> like it feels like one of the purest
forms of hacking. Like it just feels so
cool. Um and you're always talking about
it and so I just need to find some good
ones.
>> It's really fun.
>> Um okay, so let's do I'll do my big I'll
do my bigger one since we're early in
the episode. Um, this is like really
high quality content for everybody. So,
let me share my screen
>> for the viewers. Oh, by the way, I saw
you mentioning earlier on the hackalong
the like top podcast thing for Spotify.
I didn't even know that we were on
Spotify. I just I always use YouTube or
for my podcast listening, I use Overcast
or Apple podcast. So,
>> kind of interesting. Uh, we have a lot
of reviews on there. We have like 405
reviews or something. So,
>> yeah, dude. I I I think last time I
checked, I think we're around like the
200 or something like that. Uh
200 largest 200th largest uh technology
podcast.
>> That's awesome. And I'm sure it's
>> I want to get up there.
>> Yeah. Like I saw like Lex Friedman in
there. It's like it's kind of a
technology podcast, but that's more like
of a catchall. So there's probably, you
know, a good number in there that are
more catchalls that just happen to cover
tech. So it's pretty sweet.
>> Yeah. There's some there's some ones up
there though like hacked and stuff like
that that are relating to hacking in
darknet diaries of course um that are
hacking related but we are so niche in
the bug bounty world and we do really
you know push into that niche pretty
hard. We don't really stray from that
niche very much. So um I think
>> yeah which I I think that's perfect.
Like if we went way more vague it would
be so much less uh actionable for our
listeners. So
>> we'll keep it that way. Um yeah, so the
TLDDR on this is literally at the top
and so I'm just going to read it for the
audio listeners. Uh but this is a post
Yeah, this is a post by Chiron Brisenoff
um called titled how I scanned all of
GitHub's oops commits for leak secrets
and the tlddr here uh will summarize it
and then I'll hit a few high points.
Basically GitHub archive is a website
which logs every public commit even the
ones that developers try to delete. And
so that is a result of what is called
push events. Um you can just query and
I'll do that later maybe even on screen
for the viewers. Uh all GitHub events
just like they're just like streaming
out of GitHub all the time. And a guy
made a thing called a GitHub archive
like 11 years ago and it's it's archived
every single um every single event. And
so even if you force delete a specific
commit, if it was on a public repo, it's
in there forever basically. Um, so it's
kind of scary, but anyways, he scanned
all of those. They're called zero commit
force push events since 2020 and
uncovered secrets worth 25,000 in bug
bounty. Honestly, there's probably way
more in there. He's still going through
them.
>> But, um, together with truffle security,
they're actually open sourcing a tool so
that you can scan your own GitHub or for
those commit.
>> Sweet.
>> Yeah, pretty sweet. So, that's the
TLDDR. The main points that I wanted to
hit was um this quote here where it says
um he's the one who did the last one
where it was called like how I made
64,000 from deleted files. And if anyone
doesn't know this, Chiron was on the
podcast. So just Google Chiron um Bris
Bris Brisenoff.
>> Brianov.
>> Yeah. And you can find his episode. Um
but
>> in his previous one, how I made 64K from
deleted files, he talked about orphaned
blobs. But in this case there are also a
thing called orphan commits. And so
basically whenever you change the head.
So this is kind of a git nerd thing in
git. Whenever you switch the head to the
previous commit and then force push that
it basically deletes the pointer to the
previous commit that you did so that you
can't find it in git log. You can't find
it in your git commit history. You can't
find it in git tree. There's like no way
to find it. But that doesn't mean it
doesn't still exist. And it it is like a
long UU ID. So it's an unguessable idor
which you know I'm kind of famous for.
I've got the blog post on why I think
unguessable id doors are still idors.
And so it's kind of like that but it's
actually totally guessable and indexed
forever because of this thing called
GitHub archive. This is such freaking
good research man. This is classic
Chiron. This is great.
>> Yeah. So let me go down here because I
the GitHub archive bit is really
interesting. Um right here. So
eventually I came up with a simple idea.
I will use the GitHub event API
alongside the GitHub archive project to
scan all zero commit push events aka
deleted commits for secrets. Um, and so
there is a proper way to delete this
just as like a really random tidbit.
Don't do don't move your head and then
do a get force push. You have to use
what's called like get filter or
something like that. I don't know if
they even cover it in here, but if you
ask top AI models today, they'll they'll
tell you because I was like, "Oh man,
how common is this
>> for it for it to recommend?" So yeah,
here's what he says a lot of people
would do to blow away commits. They
would do get reset hard head minus one
and then push then force push that to
the origin, but this is the wrong way to
do it and the better way is called git
filter or something. So anyways, um this
GitHub archive is really neat. So I'm
going to switch to that uh tab.
>> So the GitHub archive is uh you know a
project to record all the public GitHub
timeline, archive it and make it easily
accessible. So, first of all, extremely
cool project and the fact that this has
been running since 2011 is amazing and
probably like an incredible way to um do
security research if people ever want to
do this. This may have even been the way
that some people or that like remember
whenever Shubs's team um made those word
lists. He may have used this. I'm not
sure. I don't remember. U but anyways
so let me actually show you the way that
you can pull current events from
>> is this like the stream of events?
>> Yeah. So right now Justin in your
terminal go curl https colon slash
>> what
>> api just open without any
>> no api.github.comvents
github.com/events.
>> Dude, what the heck? It's just
scrolling.
>> Yeah. So,
>> so cool.
>> Super interesting. Super cool. Yeah. I
don't know what all you can do with
this, but anyways. Uh, yeah, we've been
talking about this too long, so I'll
just I'll speedrun this. Basically, they
did this for all repos over the the
across the last 14 years and found bukus
of secrets. And then it was like, well,
how are we going to like actually filter
through these? So, they built automation
that would automatically hunt for more
impactful secrets and then they manually
tested them like the ones that are like
uh important. You know, they use things
like secret ninja and other stuff. But
then what I thought was really cool,
they didn't release this, but they they
vibe coded up their own little like
secret triage thing that would then
validate some of these cuz obviously the
majority of these can be validated in an
automated fashion. And they haven't
released that or uh shared more about it
yet, but they said that they would. I'm
pretty positive in here. But anyways,
let me show you these. So these are
secrets over time, so they trend
upwards. Makes sense as more people
commit. And then also as these old ones
kind of um get dropped off or rotated or
whatever. But um the vast majority of
secrets were MongoDB. But I mean even
these small percentages are so many that
it's still a lot. So like the there was
130 AWS keys.
>> Oh my god.
>> Yeah. They So it said they said the
MongoDB is probably um just like
students leaking non-interesting side
projects. So that's not that big of a
deal, but they but the GitHub PAT tokens
and the AWS credentials were like
obviously extremely beneficial and
generated the highest bounties. Um there
was one more thing. Okay. Yeah. My
favorite thing about this entire post
cuz you know I love fuzzing is they leak
or they list the most leaky file names.
It's a list of like 30 file names here.
I immediately added these to all of my
word list and I was missing like over
half of them. So, if you have custom
word list that you manage, go take these
right now and add them to your custom
word list because they're known good
files that have leaked passwords in the
past.
>> Dude, what the heck? Why is just the the
path unknown
>> in there? Why? That is not even one I
would check. Like, that's crazy.
>> Mhm.
>> Wow, dude.
>> Yeah. I mean, like they have read me in
here, so be careful. Like, if you don't
want noisy, like if you pick read me,
it's going to find a bunch of stuff. But
if you're doing any kind of secret
scanning or secret testing, like it it
makes sense, right? People would just
throw their keys in readme or throw in
their example, they accidentally copy
and paste in a full curl command that
has like the the credential or the
header or whatever. You know what I
mean? Like people are constantly copy
and pasting a ton of stuff into their
readme in their projects.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, I I love this,
man. And I I hope um you know with how
with how thorough Chiron in the um
truffle sack team is with these sort of
things, I'm sure they did this well, but
um I I also, you know, I hope that
they're looking at, you know, binary
format stuff, too, and and looking for
more than just um just these specific
secrets because I know that one of the
biggest bounties I've ever seen came
from a leak like this and it was a O a
certificate that was found in like this
freaking pyc file or something like
that, you know, in in a more binary
format. Um,
>> yeah, there's no way I would publish
this without giving myself like months
to go through it. So, honestly, there's
probably a lot of data and a lot of
interesting things that could be found
there. Like, even if you're just a
person who knows about a secret format
that's not in truffle hog, right? Like,
go look right now because you can
probably go find, you know, exactly
that.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. Good stuff by
Shiron as always and the truffle team.
Um, all right. Next up uh was this one.
This is by Zero. Um who we've been
talking about a lot on the pod, just
constantly cranking out good uh articles
for us to discuss. Um this one is a
little bit more of a meta article
though. It's entitled Bug Bounty
Feedback Strategy and Alchemy. Mhm.
>> Um, and there's a couple points that uh
I had throughout this one, but I always
enjoy reading, excuse me, Bug Bounty,
um, sort of meta articles.
>> Mhm.
>> Because it talks about the way people
think about the industry from a higher
perspective and can kind of elevate your
thinking um, quite a bit.
>> But, uh, you know, one of the first
things and and I know you know this as
well, we've kind of talked about this
many times. One of the things he he
shouts out on here is this line.
However, who you are, what you degrees
you hold, who you know and where you
live doesn't matter in Bug Bounty. No
interviews, no schedules, no race to
meet arbitrary standards. There are
rules, rewards, a defined scope in a
game. You discover a vulnerability
within the rules, you earn a reward. No
ceiling, no safety net, only skill
reigns. And I and I was just like,
>> dude, goosebumps, man. Like, how lucky
are we to have this skill, this thing
that we love, right? this this hobby and
then be able to implement it in a way
where we don't have to do sales, we
don't have to do client.
>> There's infinite demand for critical
vulnerabilities, right? Infinite demand.
No sales, no meetings. You can just sit
down and find bugs and that's it from
anywhere.
>> No accounting, no.
>> You don't need any overhead. It's like
you need a laptop or a phone.
>> Freaking unbelievable. Absolutely
unbelievable. Um, so I'm just so blessed
to be in this industry and I'm so
excited. Uh, and I and I I a lot of
people ask me, you know, hey, what
salary would you need to pull you away
from bug bounty hunting?
>> And sure, maybe there's a number, you
know, couple million or something like
that, but where I would just work for a
year and then just be done
>> and go back to Bug Bounty. Is that what
you're saying?
>> And go back to Bug Bounty, right? You
know, like, but but the thing is, you
know, this is what I want to be doing.
This is exactly what I want to be doing.
Um,
>> I've been thinking a lot about that.
Actually, as like a really random aside
on on the meta topic because it's this
and then you can still mention the other
things from this blog post. I feel like
I had some discontentment through the
month of May and early June ju just
feeling like I was like leaving
something on the table for some random
reason and like
>> I don't know I think that yeah honestly
might have been just a bad headsp space
but like every the thing that the
grounding thing that brought me back to
it's like what would I do like if I just
had way more money it's like oh I would
just do bug bounty hunting and like do
critical thinking so I can hang out with
Justin. It's like, so why am I trying to
like, you know, may there's probably
some other path to more money, but guess
what? I'm not willing to take those
trade-offs because I'm already at the
end, right? I don't need to get these
other means to an end because I'm at the
end. And so,
>> yeah.
>> And we've got the time and the
flexibility that we we need, right? I
know that that's big for both of us,
getting time to, you know, to spend with
the kids, to be able to help with stuff,
um,
>> and be able to do the research we love.
So,
>> freaking love it, man.
>> Me, too. um f further along and well
actually before we go into that I think
just on that note I think it's very
important for full-time bug bounty
hunters to relish the beauty of bug
bounty and the flexibility that it
affords you. So I've had a slow couple
months since we won in Tokyo, right? Um
and I love it. I loved it, you know, and
this is one of the first times where I
loved it, you know, where because I
guess over over the the time that I've
been a full-time buck bounty hunter, you
know, I've always struggled a little bit
with like, I'm taking off.
>> I'm not having getting revenue. I'm not
working. I'm not generating money. But
dude, you know what? Screw it, man. This
is exactly the time that I want to be
not working, you know, where I want to
be spending time with my kids over the
summer. Yeah. Or, you know, working on
house projects or whatever I'm doing.
Um, those are the things that I want to
prioritize and like you said, the money
is there, the money will come, it's all
good.
>> Yeah. I had to remind myself like that
this is the reason why you have runway
and this is like what you expected going
into this, like you knew there were
going to be highs and lows and so the
fact that you have to, you know, touch a
tiny bit of your runway is not like some
massive loss. It's like, oh, that's why
I have it.
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly. Exactly, man. Um, yeah. So,
anyway, going back, we took a tangent,
but going back to zero's right up here.
Um, I always love seeing these
characterizations of the hackers in the
community, right? Um, and he he says
there are lots of different styles of
hacking that can be successful. He lists
the main app guy, the recon guy, the
master automator, the lowhanging fruit
eater, the architect, the zero day
researcher, the niche specialist, the
opportunist, and the AI bot. Um, which I
I thought was great. Um, and looking at
each one of these, uh, I I think he
lists more categories than most people
do. And
>> it's almost like personality test. Like
you could keep slicing it up. Different
people have different perspectives. It
but it's still always kind of
interesting and fun. That's how I view
it. It's like, yeah, some people fall in
multiple categories. Some people have
all the skills. Some people are not
going to fit these categories, but I I
always like reading them anyways, and I
think that they're really fun to think
about. Yeah, I'm trying to find I can't
find that write up by Codingo, but
Codingo also does a good article on the
Bug Crowd blog, sort of talking about
the the recon guy, the main app guy or
whatever. Um I I really did like Zero's
representation of it, though, because um
he says specifically that he recommends
the niche specialist, and this is what
he he um he says specializes in one type
or family of vulnerabilities and masters
it better than, you know, x% of the
hunters. Finds what others miss, rises
above the competition. Its relevance
depends on a choice of specialization,
which I'll come back to a little bit
later. If the choices are good, it can
obviously make money frequently. This is
what I've recommended in the past. Um,
and yeah, I think that's great. You
know, going I mean, obviously this
person is a, uh, specialist in cash
poisoning related vulnerabilities. So,
uh, he's definitely got some bias there.
Uh, you know, but I I think the niche
specialist is always, uh, a really good
way to go if you want to start making
money in Bug Bounty.
>> Well, I think there's a couple reasons
why, too. Like one is the fact that uh
you do have to it's a skill game, right?
Like we just talked about that you have
to beat out other people. And so there's
a couple ways that you can beat them
out, right? Like if you wanted to be a
recon guy or you want to be a low
hanging fruit, you got to be faster and
you got to stay on top of other people,
right? Whereas if you just have if
you're just the most skilled in a
specific thing, not only can you find
those by yourself, but people will drive
deals to you, right? It's the same
reason why people go to Chapman for
headless Chrome bugs, right? it there
there's enough of you front end guys
where it's kind of dispersed but in
general you all all get a lot of people
reaching out with front end vans right
>> I think that um it really helped me
especially earlier this year as people
came to me whenever they were dealing
with like AI vans
>> and so I think that having a specialty
>> doesn't exclude you from like spraying
that specialty like let's say you're a
big XSS guy and you find XSS in like a
third party library or in like a a
specific thing now you can spray it and
you can still be a recon person with
your knee specialty um and you can grab
low hanging fruit with your niche
specialty. I think the niche specialist
is like defensible against AI and also
um useful because it drives deals your
way in the form of networking and
collaborations. But then also even if
you didn't have those, you could just go
find that bug other places and it's
going to exist there because you're
better at finding it than other people.
So it's at a higher skill level. So it's
kind of withheld from the crowd just for
you.
>> Absolutely, man. I love what you said,
but you lost me when you slapped your
mic.
I did. Listen, I've been trying not to
touch it. I've been muting it when I
need to touch it. I was told I touched
it too much in the past.
>> Dude, I I I also touch my mic a lot. So,
hey guys, I'm sorry. Like like Richard,
we're so sorry. Listeners, we're so
sorry. Like we're we're hackers. We're
not podcasters. So, uh Richard does our
does the best he can with our like crap
audio we give him.
>> Where's our NATO?
>> Yelling. Exactly. Dude, I Dude, my
needle broke. My NATO broke. I can't
squeeze it anymore. So sad. Anyway, it's
bringing it back around. Um, la last
little quote I wanted to read from this
article um was this one. This one's a
little bit longer, but but hang in
there. Okay, so it says, "Money has been
discussed a lot here. Nothing unusual
from the perspective of a full-time
independent bug bounty hunter. Uh, but
it's time to aim higher, to seek to move
things forward in your field and do your
part. I find it fascinating that much of
the technology we use today is a result
of vast of a vast stack of universal
knowledge built on over centuries by
countless contributors. narrowing it
down, you've probably reached this level
thanks to numerous research papers,
courses, videos shared for free by
people around the world. Aren't you in
some way indebted to that stack? Now,
it's your turn to contribute with
research papers, novel findings,
presentations, useful tools, and simply
some good advice. If it worked for you,
it might work for others, too. Um, and I
thought that, dude, I thought I was I
was moved, man. I was moved a little bit
in the heart, you know, like we all are
standing on the shoulders of giants in
this industry and uh it it has made me
really happy especially to see um some
of the guys in the critical thinking
community like like demo turbo right um
you know doing these talks at at Defcon
or um you know there's lots of people
contributing back um and it's really
>> let let me have my hot take then so
>> I definitely agree I think that the
cyber security industry is extremely
unique relative relative to other
industries. Like I actually think that
um
I actually think that it is more
different and unique in this way than
any other industry. Like I don't think
there's any other industry where people
give back as much as they do. Every time
I every time I meet a security guy, a
security person who like goes to
conferences all the time, security
conferences, like does talks and stuff,
I'm always like kind of shocked and
almost off-put by the fact they do that
for free. Like the vast majority of
speakers at conferences are going to
these random conferences and so many of
them are in little small towns and
they're on the side track and they're
presenting to 10 people who are never
going to use their research and they
still like love to do it and they love
to go and they put in hours into these
like presentations and sometimes they
get on YouTube and they do well or
whatever like they go into the video
archives and sometimes people do find
them and use them. But I one think
that's extremely impressive and really
cool. I also think it creates a culture
of not wanting to pay for information.
And so I I'm not like a course maker,
right? I've done one $200 course which
was like very bleeding edge like
information on like the zero to hero of
agent hacking. But like outside of that,
I've done no courses. And there are
people who do like really good courses
and really good training. And also like
I think that there are a lot of speakers
that are good enough and I think are
worthy of being paid to go places that
like can't get paid to do it because
like the security industry is like so
sharing. So I don't know. I don't know
if there's like a big fix for that and I
don't even know if it's a real complaint
because I do think that is incredible in
a lot of ways. But I also think that it
does create an industry that is like
really reticent to pay for products and
reticent to pay for because they're so
pro open source also and so reticent to
pay for information. M that is that is a
an interesting take on that. You know I
I think yeah it would it does affect you
know the ability to get paid for some of
these things. Um
>> but anyways I mean we also give a ton of
free information away every week here on
critical thinking. So and I and I love
doing it and it's a it's a privilege. It
is. That's right.
>> Lots of fun man. Um that's all I had on
my list. Do you have anything else you
wanted to throw on here at the end of
the podcast?
>> Um yeah I'll just throw in something
really quick because I think it's so
cool and incredible. And speaking of
free information, actually, wow, I did
not mean I did not intend this segue,
guys. Um, but Google released, let me
make sure I pop down my messages before
I share my screen. I always accidentally
share my Twitter message, so I have to
edit it out. Um, so,
>> uh, basically, Google released their
entire playbook and project, uh, the
entire paper and all of the open source
code for their prompt injection
protection that they actually use across
their products.
Um, I'm sure it's not 100%, you know, of
what they're using, but it is massively
underrated, only 40 stars here with only
six forks. It was released 3 weeks ago,
and it is
>> like uh their paper defeating prompt
injection by design, which, you know,
we've uh encountered a lot in our
hacking, how how good they are at
defending prompt injection relative to
other um other companies and other
organizations. And it's by using a thing
called camel, which stands for
something. I don't even know what it
stands for, but um but anyways, they
released um this repo that shows how to
use it and all of that. And I when they
released this, I was like kind of blown
away that they had released it because
this feels like the bleeding edge like
the you know frontline best research for
prompt injection protection at scale.
And so if you're a company out there or
even if you're a hacker, I think diving
into this would be a really uh
worthwhile endeavor.
>> Yeah, totally. Man, this I'm very
surprised they put this out.
>> Yeah, me too.
>> That's uh that's really cool. Definitely
something I feel like Ronnie has already
like consumed, you know. Yeah. Uh after
struggling with that for so long at the
at the event. Yeah. So,
>> very fun. All right, man. Uh that's a
wrap on this one. Um cool stuff. I I I
enjoyed today's episode. I was I was not
going to lie. I was a little tired.
Anytime we record an episode after I do
the hackalong, you know, and I had this
morning,
>> I, you know, my social energy is low and
I'm like trying to turtle up a little
bit, but this is a good one.
>> Yeah, you did well. Thanks, man. Thanks,
guys.
>> Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.